<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Technical Implementation</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p></p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage><language ident="eng">Englisch</language></langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <p>
                This source edition is a model project for testing and improving existing digital
                infrastructures. The project takes advantage of open source solutions and integrates
                common standard formats for digital editions. It also includes long-term archiving
                for MODS (catalog data), METS (digitized content), TEI P5 (text tagging of the
                transcripts and translations), DOI (persistent identification), GND-Beacon files,
                and the MyCoRe viewer.<note type="editorial" place="foot"
                    ><ref target="http://www.mycore.de/documentation/frontend/imageviewer.pdf">www.mycore.de/documentation/frontend/imageviewer.pdf</ref> (Accessed August
                    29, 2016).</note> It combines these with a user-friendly presentation in a
                common open source framework.<note type="editorial" place="foot"
                    >The source code is available at <ref target="https://github.com/burki/jewish-history-online">github.com/burki/jewish-history-online</ref> (Accessed April 21, 2017)</note> Digitization has been carried out following the
                practical guidelines “Digitalisierung” established by the Deutsche
                Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG).<note type="editorial" place="foot"
                    ><ref target="http://www.dfg.de/formulare/12_151/12_151_de.pdf">www.dfg.de/formulare/12_151/12_151_de.pdf</ref> (Accessed August 29,
                    2016).</note> All digital files, TEI files, and metadata are also stored for
                long-term archiving as a METS Container in an instance of the MyCoRe
                    repository.<note type="editorial" place="foot">Due to our cooperation with the
                    University of Hamburg’s Regionals Rechenzentrum as partner for digital long-term
                    archiving the MyCoRe platform primarily used there was chosen for this
                    project.</note> The digitized records (facsimiles), transcripts (full text), and
                translations are embedded into a visually appealing frontend by means of a viewer
                plug-in for METS Container, which is connected to the repository by an OAI
                interface. </p>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

