<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Project Staff</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>
                    <orgName>Institut für die Geschichte der deutschen Juden</orgName>
                    <email>redaktion@juedische-geschichte-online.net</email>
                    <address><addrLine>Beim Schlump 83, 20144 Hamburg</addrLine></address>
                </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Hamburg</pubPlace>
                <date type="publication">2016-09-01</date>
                <availability>
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">
                        <p>Dieser Text unterliegt den Bedingungen der Creative Commons Namensnennung - Nicht kommerziell - Keine Bearbeitungen 4.0 International Lizenz. Unter Namensnenung gemäß dem Zitationshinweis darf er in unveränderter Form für nicht-kommerzielle Zwecke nachgenutzt werden.</p>
                    </licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage><language ident="eng">Englisch</language></langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div n="3">
                <head>Project Staff</head><lb/>
                
                <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="http://www.igdj-hh.de/daniel-burckhardt.html">Daniel Burckhardt, M.A.</ref></hi> (Technology)<lb/></p>
                <p>Mr. Burckhardt has been as Research Associate at the Institute for the History of the German Jews since 2015. Daniel Burckhardt studied in Zürich and Berlin and was previously engaged as Research Associate at the Institute for the Historical Sciences, Humboldt University Berlin and at the Centre for Contemporary History Potsdam (ZZF). In addition, he is a member of the editorial board and Steering Committee of <ref target="http://www.hsozkult.de/">H-Soz-Kult</ref> based at Humboldt University.
                </p>
                                
                <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="http://www.igdj-hh.de/dr-anna-menny.html">Dr. Anna Menny</ref></hi> (Project coordinator)<lb/></p>
                <p>Dr. Menny has been a Research Associate at the Institute for the History of the German Jews since 2012, and coordinates the online source edition. Her research work deals with Jewish-Spanish history, and questions pertaining to the culture of memory and the Digital Humanities.</p>
                
                <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="http://www.igdj-hh.de/dr-miriam-ruerup.html">Dr. Miriam Rürup</ref></hi> (Project director)<lb/></p>
                <p>Dr. Rürup has been director of the Institute for the History of the German Jews since 2012 and initiated the online source edition Key Documents on German-Jewish History (Hamburger Schlüsseldokumente zur deutsch-jüdischen Geschichte), which provides a window onto Jewish history in Hamburg on various levels of depth, rendering them visible and accessible. Her research deals with German-Jewish history, contemporary history, the history of National Socialism, the politics of commemoration, gender history, and from the area of her habilitation thesis, especially the history of migration, citizenship and statelessness.<lb/></p>
                
            </div>
            
            <div n="3">
                <head>Student assistants</head><lb/>
                <p><hi rendition="#b">Ute Schumacher, B.A.</hi><lb/></p>
                <p>She is a student majoring in cultural anthropology at the University of Hamburg. Her research interests center on the history of Shoah, visual culture, urban anthropology, gender studies.</p><lb/>
                
                <p><hi rendition="#b">Esther Yen, B.A.</hi></p><lb/>
                <p>She studies Islamic studies at Hamburg University. Her research interests are: the history of Islam in Germany, reform movements in the Middle East, memorial sites and remembrance policy. </p><lb/>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Former Staff</head><lb/>
                <p><hi rendition="#b">Dr. Inka Le-Huu</hi> (Editorial team)</p><lb/>
                <p>Dr. Le-Huu has been a Research Associate at the Institute for the History of the German Jews from 2014 until 2016. She was awarded a grant from the German National Academic Foundation (Studienstiftung des deutschen Volkes) and is Lecturer in Public History in the Department of History at the University of Hamburg. Her research deals with German-Jewish history in the 19th century and local history in Hamburg. 
                </p><lb/>
                
                <p><hi rendition="#b">Nina Zellerhoff, M.A.</hi> (Editorial team)</p><lb/>
                <p>Ms. Zellerhoff has been a Research Associate at the Institute for the History of the German Jews from 2016 until 2017. Her research work deals with the initializing and establishment of memorial sites, questions pertaining to the culture of memory and the future of commemoration. Her research interests center on German-Jewish contemporary history, the history of National Socialism and the Digital Humanities.<lb/></p>                
                
                <p><hi rendition="#b">Renée Grothkopf</hi></p><lb/>
                <p>She is a student majoring in sociology and history at the University of Hamburg. Her research interests center on studies in anti-Semitism, economic critique and gender studies. <lb/></p>
                
                <p><hi rendition="#b">Clara Hestermann, B.A.</hi></p><lb/>
                <p>Ms. Hestermann is a student majoring in history and political science at the University of Hamburg. Her research interests center on Jewish history, European history of the 20th century and history of the Near East.<lb/></p>
                
                <p><hi rendition="#b">Jan Kawlath, B.A.</hi></p><lb/>
                <p>He received a degree in history and philosophy at the University of Hamburg. His research interests lie in German colonial history, genocide research and post-colonialism.<lb/></p>

                <p><hi rendition="#b">Sebastian Merkel, M.A.</hi></p><lb/>
                <p>He received a degree in history at the University of Hamburg. Mr. Merkel’s research interests center on the history of internment camps and violence in the 20th century, youth (sub)cultures and German contemporary history.<lb/></p>

                <p><hi rendition="#b">Irina Troitskaya, B.A.</hi></p><lb/>
                <p>She studies history and politics at the University of Hamburg. Her research interests are: Eastern European History (History of the Soviet Union), European History in 20th century, especially Nationalsocialism and culture of remembrance in Western and Eastern Europe. </p><lb/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>


