<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Guidelines for the Use of Materials in the Key Documents
                    Edition</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p></p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage><language ident="eng">English</language></langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <p>The source edition “Key Documents of German-Jewish History” is published by the <ref
                    target="http://www.igdj-hh.de/home-175.html">Institute for the History of German
                    Jews</ref> (IGdJ) and is conceived as open access content for academic use.</p>
            <lb/>
            <p>All documents and articles are provided with information on copyright and licenses
                and suggestions for proper citation.</p>
            <lb/>
            <div n="4">
                <head>Possibilities for academic use and for use in teaching</head>
                <lb/>
                <p>The introductions and source interpretations are usually published under the
                    license “<ref target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0/deed.en">CC
                        BY-NC-ND 4.0</ref>” (Attribution: author name, article, in: Key Documents of
                    German-Jewish History, date, URL). This allows for secondary use of the unedited
                    text on condition of full citation for academic and other non-commercial
                    purposes., e. g. for use in the classroom. Whenever a text is used, the
                    information on copyright and permission given in the suggestions for citation
                    must be included. In the case of excerpted citation, any omissions and changes
                    must be indicated.</p>
                <lb/>
                <p>The copyrights to the digitized images featured in the source edition are usually
                    held by the preserving institutions. For questions concerning the reproduction
                    of images, for example in publications, interested parties should contact the
                    institutions holding them directly.</p>
                <lb/>
                <p> Where legally possible, an option is provided to download the sources for
                    scholarly purposes or for use in teaching, for example, as part of a lecture /
                    presentation or for the production of class materials (non-commercial). However,
                    any kind of publication (online or print) is only permitted if the digital copy
                    is provided explicitly under a corresponding Creative Commons license or as
                    public domain.</p>
                <lb/>
                <p> The same applies to the use of transcripts. Suggestion for correct citation
                    mentioning the “Key Documents” edition as proper origin can be found on the
                    respective page.</p>
                <lb/>
                <p> Additional information on licensing can be found under <ref
                        target="http://juedische-geschichte-online.net/nutzungsbedingungen">Terms
                        and Conditions</ref>.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
