<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">About Us</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>
                    <orgName>Institut für die Geschichte der deutschen Juden</orgName>
                    <email>redaktion@juedische-geschichte-online.net</email>
                    <address><addrLine>Beim Schlump 83, 20144 Hamburg</addrLine></address>
                </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Hamburg</pubPlace>
                <date type="publication">2016-09-01</date>
                <availability>
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">
                        <p>Dieser Text unterliegt den Bedingungen der Creative Commons Namensnennung - Nicht kommerziell - Keine Bearbeitungen 4.0 International Lizenz. Unter Namensnenung gemäß dem Zitationshinweis darf er in unveränderter Form für nicht-kommerzielle Zwecke nachgenutzt werden.</p>
                    </licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage><language ident="eng">Englisch</language></langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div n="2">
                <!-- <head>The Project</head> -->
                <p>This online source edition published by the Institute for the History of German
                    Jews (IGdJ) uses a selection of sources, so-called key documents, to
                    thematically highlight central aspects in Hamburg’s Jewish history from the
                    early modern age to the present. The editors consider Hamburg as a lens for
                    larger developments and questions in German-Jewish history. The source edition
                    aims to help digitally reunite the city’s Jewish heritage, scattered all over
                    the world due to persecution and migration, and to make it accessible and
                    preserve it for future generations. <lb/></p>
                <p>By presenting previously little studied sources and putting familiar archival
                    documents in new contexts and formats we hope to give thought-provoking impulses
                    and encourage new lines of study. The sources are at the center of this project,
                    inspiring discussion about specific interpretations and categorizations.
                    <lb/></p>
                <p>Transcripts as well as digital facsimiles are provided for all sources, which are
                    placed in historical context by interpretations and background information. The
                    source material is further enriched by information on its provenance, historical
                    responses to it, and scholarly controversies. All content is provided in both
                    German and English. <lb/></p>
                <p>The target audience for this source edition is college students, researchers and
                    teachers, as well as the interested public and high school students. It covers a
                    spectrum ranging from more general, introductory texts to those developing their
                    argument by a close study of the source, and it offers different ways of
                    approaching the texts—through a timeline, a specific topic or a map. The project
                    is supported by an advisory board consisting of renowned scholars of
                    German-Jewish history and experts in the field of digitization.<lb/></p>
                <p>The online edition receives funding from the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft for
                    a two-year period that began in July 2015. With this edition the IGdJ once again
                    fulfils its role as an institution serving as a link between scholarship and the
                    interested public.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>


