<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Goals</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p></p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage><language ident="en">Englisch</language></langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <p>The main goals of this edition are to impart knowledge about Jewish history through
                sources, to make larger contexts comprehensible through specific examples, and to
                facilitate access to these sources and thus encourage new research. Furthermore, it
                represents a contribution to the preservation and study of Jewish heritage. In
                publishing this edition, it is our intention to provide a new perspective on
                Hamburg’s Jewish history while making a technical contribution to the long-term
                preservation of key sources.</p>
            <lb/>
            <p>By presenting previously little studied sources and putting familiar archival
                documents in new contexts and formats we hope to give thought-provoking impulses and
                encourage new lines of study. The fact that the arguments made are based directly on
                the sources encourages debate on specific interpretations and categorizations.
                Hamburg’s Jewish history is considered in a national, transnational, and global
                context. Beyond their significance for local history, the sources are meant to “open
                doors” to understanding broader developments and questions in (German-)Jewish
                history. </p>
            <lb/>
            <p>The source interpretations which provide critical commentary on the documents as well
                as context on their history are informed by current research. Thus it is ensured
                that the edition reflects current scholarly debate while the commentary also serves
                the purpose of contextualizing a source that has been taken out of its original
                place of discovery. In order to include findings from current research projects, we
                specifically encouraged the participation of junior scholars in our project.</p>
            <lb/>
            <p>Making sources available on the internet not only increases their visibility and
                accessibility, the edition also seeks to digitally reunite Hamburg’s Jewish
                heritage, which has been scattered all over the world, and to preserve it for future
                generations (and scholars). The English translations provided for all source
                material are intended to facilitate the inclusion of sources on Hamburg’s Jewish
                history in comparative transnational studies or in academic curricula outside
                Germany.</p>
            <lb/>
            <p>Since the online source edition is conceived of as a model project, it is also
                intended to provide new insights into the use of digitization in the field of Jewish
                history and document these. These may include the practical application of existing
                digital tools or the tagging of heterogeneous source material. Experiences
                concerning the possible improvement and testing of subject-specific requirements
                such as thesauri, multilingual versions of sources or tagging texts including Hebrew
                characters will be of particular interest in this process. Being anchored in the
                discipline of history, we hope this edition will increase the acceptance of digital
                publications and provide guidance on their critical use.</p>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
