<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Key Documents</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p></p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage><language ident="eng">Englisch</language></langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <p>This source edition does not represent a complete set of archival holdings, but is
                composed of documents selected from different archives and institutions based on
                their content. Longer texts or expansive image files/audiovisual documents are
                excerpted to present key passages or parts of this source. Where the rights could be
                obtained, both the excerpted version (annotated according to our edition guidelines)
                and the entire source are included; if a digitized version of a source already
                exists, a link is included. The main criterion for source selection is the idea of
                “key documents.”</p>
            <lb/>
            <p>The term key documents describes selected sources which are used as examples to
                provide insight into historical contexts and events. Key documents are supposed to
                “open doors” leading to a better and more vivid understanding of history. Whether
                these are well-known records – such as by-laws and other legal documents – or
                previously little studied sources, efforts were consistently made to ensure the
                representative character of the entire volume of documents. The selection of the
                interpreted and edited sources is a result of close cooperation between the
                editorial staff, the authors, and editors.</p>
            <lb/>
            <p>The following criteria were central to the selection of sources which include texts,
                images, sound recordings, and audiovisual files.</p>
            <lb/>
            <p>The source has to…
                <list>
                    <item>connect to a broader historical context / pose questions</item>
                    <item>represent an example from a larger volume of sources or tell a
                        “typical” story because of its uniqueness</item>
                    <item>be clearly identifiable based on
                        extensive information on the source (time of creation, author, etc.)</item>
                    
                </list>
            </p>
            <lb/>
            <p>The basic idea is that each source and its commentary should be closely connected in
                order to allow references back to the source and inferences from it in a manner that
                is as transparent as possible. The reader is encouraged to not just follow the
                interpretation, but attempt their own interpretation. In order to ensure this,
                focusing on short documents seemed necessary.</p>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
