<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Editors</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>
                    <orgName>Institut für die Geschichte der deutschen Juden</orgName>
                    <email>redaktion@juedische-geschichte-online.net</email>
                    <address><addrLine>Beim Schlump 83, 20144 Hamburg</addrLine></address>
                </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Hamburg</pubPlace>
                <date type="publication">2016-09-01</date>
                <availability>
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">
                        <p>Dieser Text unterliegt den Bedingungen der Creative Commons Namensnennung - Nicht kommerziell - Keine Bearbeitungen 4.0 International Lizenz. Unter Namensnenung gemäß dem Zitationshinweis darf er in unveränderter Form für nicht-kommerzielle Zwecke nachgenutzt werden.</p>
                    </licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage><language ident="en">Englisch</language></langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/gnd/124481701">Werner Bergmann</ref></hi>
                    (<ref target="../topic/antisemitism-and-persecution">Antisemitism and
                    Persecution</ref>), Prof. Dr. Werner Bergmann, is Professor at the Centre for
                Research on Antisemitism, Technical University of Berlin. His research interests
                centre on the sociology and history of Antisemitism and related fields, such as
                racism and right-wing extremism.</p>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/gnd/121216926">Andreas Brämer</ref></hi>
                    (<ref target="../topic/religion-and-identity">Religion and Identity</ref>), PD
                Dr. phil., Deputy Director of the Institute for the History
                of the German Jews, is a member of the board of the
                Wissenschaftliche Arbeitsgemeinschaft (Academic Working Group) of the Leo Baeck
                Institute. His research foci include German-Jewish history of the 19th and 20th
                century, Jewish history "from the inside", Jewish religious history and the history
                of Jewish historiography. </p>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/gnd/1022870408">Tobias Brinkmann</ref></hi>
                    (<ref target="../topic/migration">Migration</ref>), Dr. phil., is Malvin and Lea
                Bank Associate Professor of Jewish Studies and History in the Department of History
                at Penn State University. His research interests focus on the history of migration,
                especially Jewish migration from Central and Eastern Europe to North America.</p>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/gnd/1053233884">Stefanie Fischer</ref></hi>
                    (<ref target="../topic/family-and-everyday-life">Family and Everyday
                Life</ref>), Dr. phil., holds a postdoc position at the Center for Jewish Studies,
                Berlin-Brandenburg. In her current research project, she is examining the
                post-genocidal relationships of Jewish Holocaust survivors to their former German
                home towns in the 1950s/1960s. In her PhD thesis, she investigated the
                interrelationship between economic trust and anti-Semitic violence as exemplified by
                the German-Jewish cattle dealers between 1919 and 1939. </p>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/gnd/115282572">Kirsten Heinsohn</ref></hi>
                    (<ref target="../topic/leisure-and-sports">Leisure and Sports</ref>), PD Dr.
                phil., served as Associate Professor in the Department of English, Germanic and
                Romance Studies at the University of Copenhagen from 2013-2015. Since 2015, she has
                served as Deputy Director of the Research Centre for Contemporary History in
                Hamburg. Her research foci comprise modern German history, German-Jewish history and
                gender history.</p>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/gnd/129847437">Uffa Jensen</ref></hi> (<ref
                    target="../topic/law-and-politics">Law and Politics</ref>, <ref
                    target="../topic/economy-and-occupational-composition">Economy and Occupational
                    Patterns</ref>), Dr. phil., is Research Associate in the Research Group “History
                of Emotions”, Max Planck Institute for Human Development in Berlin. Among his
                research interests are the history of knowledge and science, transnational history,
                history of psychoanalysis, modern Jewish history and the history of
                anti-Semitism.</p>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/gnd/121749401">Anthony D.
                    Kauders</ref></hi> (<ref target="../topic/arts-and-culture">Arts and
                    Culture</ref>), Dr. phil., is Deputy Director of history at Keele University and
                Reader for Modern European History. He is currently doing research on the history of
                hypnosis, social psychology and psychotherapy.</p>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/gnd/124838464">Rainer Liedtke</ref></hi>
                    (<ref target="../topic/">Organizations and Institutions</ref>), Prof. Dr. phil.,
                is Professor of 19th and 20th Century European History at the University of
                Regensburg. His research interests centre on comparative European history, urban
                history, Jewish history, British history and the modern history of Greece.</p>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/gnd/110785991">Ingrid Lohmann</ref></hi>
                    (<ref target="../topic/education-and-learning">Education and Learning</ref>),
                Prof. Dr. phil, is Professor of the History of Ideas and Social History of Education
                at the University of Hamburg. Her research interests include the relations between
                economy and education since the beginning of the modern period, especially
                privatization and commercialization in the education and research sector, as well as
                Jewish history of education, focusing on the late Enlightenment in Germany.</p>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/gnd/140136541">Beate Meyer</ref></hi> (<ref
                    target="../topic/memory-and-remembrance">Memory and Remembrance</ref>), Dr.
                phil., is a Research Associate at the Institute for the History of the German Jews. Her research interests are focused on aspects of German-Jewish history,
                National Socialism, oral history, gender history and cultures of memory.</p>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/gnd/136259103">Miriam Rürup</ref></hi>
                    (<ref target="../topic/demographics-and-social-structure">Demographics and
                    Social Structure</ref>), Dr. phil., is director of the Institute for the History
                of the German Jews. Her research deals with gender history, German-Jewish
                history, contemporary history, history of migration, history of students and
                universities, history of the politics of commemoration and the history of National
                Socialism.</p>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/gnd/114053766">Stefanie
                        Schüler-Springorum</ref></hi> (<ref
                    target="../topic/social-issues-and-welfare">Social Issues and Welfare</ref>),
                Prof. Dr. phil., has served as Director of the Centre for Research on Anti-Semitism
                at the Technical University of Berlin since 2011 and has represented the Technical University Berlin
                within the Council of Directors at the Centre Jewish Studies Berlin-Brandenburg
                since 2012. She held the post of Director of the Institute for the History of the
                German Jews in Hamburg from 2001 to 2011.</p>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/gnd/112201873">Michael
                        Studemund-Halévy</ref></hi> (<ref target="../topic/sephardic-jews">Sephardic
                    Jews</ref>), docteur ès-lettres, is Eduard Duckesz-Fellow at the Institute for
                the history of the German Jews. His fields of research center Western Sefardic
                Diaspora, Hebrew epigraphy and iconography, Jewish Languages and Judeospanish.</p>
            <p><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="../person/249">Lilian Türk</ref></hi> (<ref
                    target="../topic/scholarship">Scholarship</ref>), Dr. phil., is a Research
                Associate at the Institute for Jewish Philosophy and Religion, University of
                Hamburg. Her primary research interests lie in Yiddish religious phenomenology,
                Yiddish language and literature, the role of the Yiddish press in social movements
                between 1850 and 1950, and non-conformist Jewish identities, particularly in the
                context of religious anarchism.</p>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>



