<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Become an Author</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p></p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <p>On occasion of this year's 50th anniversary, the Institute for the History of the
                German Jews (IGdJ) published a digital source edition on "Key documents of
                German-Jewish History", which was launched during the "Historikertag" (51st Biennial
                Meeting of German Historians) in Hamburg.</p>
            <p> The digital source edition, which is funded by the German Research Foundation (DFG),
                illustrates central thematic aspects of Hamburg's Jewish history from the Early
                Modern Period to the present. The editorial team understands Hamburg hereby as a
                model for broader developments and questions of German-Jewish history.</p>
            <p> In order to extend the edition, the IGdJ is looking for scholars who are interested
                in presenting and discussing questions and findings from their research by using a
                concrete historical source. </p>
            <p> The bilingual source edition (English / German) is mainly intended for students and
                researchers, but it also wants to provide insight into the subject to the interested
                broader public and high school students. The materials will be presented as
                transcripts and facsimile and will be embedded in their historical contexts with the
                help of interpretative texts providing information about the historical context,
                historiographic reception and academic controversies. </p>
            <p> All material can be accessed via three different approaches: a map, a timeline and
                thematic topics. These thematic categories are supervised by editors and are
                introduced by an article that gives a general overview to the topic. </p>
            <p> More sources and interpretative texts are
                planned to be successively published on the website of the digital source edition.
                Therefore, we welcome articles in all thematic categories, as long as they are connected to the
                Jewish history of Hamburg. </p>
            <p> A short description of the source (150-200 words) and an interpretative text (1500
                words) are needed for the digital source edition. The interpretative articles can be
                written in German or English. Possible sources are text documents, pictures, audio
                documents and video sections as well as objects. </p>
            <p>
                <hi rendition="#i">Please send proposals for sources and an informative outline of
                    the respective interpretative article, shortly depicting the source and its
                    historical context,  to Dr. Anna Menny (<ref
                        target="mailto:anna.menny@igdj-hh.de">anna.menny@igdj-hh.de</ref>). Please
                    add a short CV. Furthermore, please provide a preliminary reference to the usage
                    rights. We explicitly encourage young researchers to apply. </hi>
            </p>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
