<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Target audience</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p></p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage><language ident="eng">Englisch</language></langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <p>
                The edition is mainly intended for college students, researchers, and teachers in the
                field of Jewish history, but it also wants to provide insight into the subject to
                the interested public and high school students. Online publications in particular
                are faced with a challenge that also represents an opportunity: each user picks
                topics of interest to them and uses digital content according to an arbitrary, often
                random logic that cannot be compared to reading a book one has picked up. Thus users
                who might not be reached by a traditional, printed source edition might be randomly
                directed to the online version by a search engine. It is impossible to predict where
                a user will begin reading an online edition. While one can assume that the reader of
                a printed edition will begin by looking at the table of contents or the index, an
                online edition must be accessible to the reader in all possible ways: traditionally
                by starting with the home page or the index as well as by following a direct link to
                a source. We do not expect a focused reading of this online edition from an assumed
                “beginning” to an assumed “end.” Therefore this edition seeks to provide information
                to random visitors just as thoroughly as to those who visit it for a specific
                purpose. The index, a key element of the printed edition, is also included in the
                online version.</p>
            <lb/>
            <p>By providing bilingual, digital versions of the edited sources accompanied by
                introductions written by well-known scholars in the field online, we hope to reach
                German- and English-speaking junior scholars in particular.</p>
            <lb/>
            <p>Since online projects provide the opportunity to expand the (potential) audience of
                users beyond a local and regional target audience, all material is also made
                available in English. Among other things, this is an expression of the IGdJ’s
                growing international contacts, which have been further expanded in recent years,
                and of its networking with international scholars. Moreover, it reflects the history
                of Jewish sourcesscattered widely beyond the city of Hamburg and allows the
                descendants of Jewish former Hamburg citizens to connect with the urban history of
                their ancestors.</p>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
