<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Structure / How to Use this Edition</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p></p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage><language ident="en">Englisch</language></langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <p>Being extremely user-friendly and offering extensive research tools, this online
                edition is attractive to the general interested public as well. Different <hi
                    rendition="#b">text genres</hi> and various <hi rendition="#b">types of
                    sources</hi> such as images or sound and video recordings provide information on
                German-Jewish history on different levels. The edition has a modular structure so
                that the sources can be researched by users via three different paths: a timeline, a
                map or a thematic module.
            </p>
            
            <div n="2">
                <head>Text Genres and Types of Sources</head><lb/>
                <p>The online edition thematically highlights key aspects of local, regional, and
                    general German-Jewish history by using a sample of currently 50 (about 150 once this
                    phase of the project is completed) key documents. The number of these key documents
                    could certainly be increased. There are different text levels in order to integrate
                    the sources into their historical context as well as into scholarly debate.</p>
                <lb/>
                <p>A general overview is provided by the <hi rendition="#b">first text genre</hi>, the
                    <ref target="../topic"><hi rendition="#b"><hi rendition="#i">introductions</hi></hi> to the currently
                        15 subject categories</ref>. Written by <ref target="editors">different editors</ref>, these introductions represent
                    the most detailed and profound text genre in terms of content. In contrast to a
                    printed historical introduction, they do not follow a common narrative and can thus
                    be read independently of one another. In some cases thematic aspects will therefore
                    be repeated in different introductions, all of which stand alone yet complement each
                    other content wise. The introductions are the longest texts in the edition. Their
                    purpose is to place the sources in the broader historical context.</p>
                <lb/>
                <p>The selection of subject categories offers a multi-perspective access to the
                    circumstances shaping Jewish life, and it captures important aspects of life within
                    the Jewish communities on various levels without trying to establish a
                    metanarrative. The categories are meant to present the diverse facets of Jewish life
                    rather than reduce Jewish history to a history of persecution and/or contribution.
                    The underlying idea of the thematic introductions is that a specific thematic focus
                    opens up a path into German-Jewish history which will then lead to further
                    questions. Someone only interested in the topic of “law and politics” initially
                    might thus be directed to the topic of “leisure and sports” by clicking a link to a
                    source. On the one hand, the selection of subject categories is arrived at by
                    processof induction from the sources – in the case of categories such as “leisure
                    and sports” or “arts and culture,” for example. On the other hand, the editorial
                    staff is aware that a certain basic thematic structure similar to a historical
                    introduction is necessary, and therefore introductions on “demographics and social
                    structure” and “economy and occupational patterns” are provided as well.</p>
                <lb/>
                <p><hi rendition="#b">The individual subject categories are:</hi>
                    <lb/>• Antisemitism and Persecution <lb/>• Arts and Culture <lb/>• Economy and
                    Occupational Patterns <lb/>• Education and Learning <lb/>• Everyday Life and Family
                    <lb/>• Demographics and Social Structure <lb/>• Law and Politics <lb/>• Leisure and
                    Sports <lb/>• Memory and Remembrance <lb/>• Migration <lb/>• Organizations and
                    Institutions <lb/>• Religion and Identity <lb/>• Social Questions and Welfare <lb/>•
                    Scholarship <lb/>• Sephardic Jews </p>
                <lb/>
                <p>The core of the edition consists of the <hi rendition="#b">second text genre</hi>,
                    the <hi rendition="#b"><hi rendition="#i">sources</hi></hi>. Most of the edited
                    sources are texts, but non-textual sources are read as texts as well. Whenever
                    possible sources are presented in their entirety; only in some cases have clips or
                    excerpts been chosen instead. The length of the sources has been limited for reasons
                    of content as well as for practical reasons: firstly, a short text allows the
                    interpretation to discuss single aspects in depth and to closely examine individual
                    sentences or phrases which cannot be discussed as thoroughly when interpreting a
                    longer text. Secondly, the brevity of the texts is necessitated by the medium and
                    online reading habits.</p>
                <lb/>
                <p><hi rendition="#b"><hi rendition="#i">Source interpretations</hi></hi> represent the
                    <hi rendition="#b">third text genre</hi>. Their function is to “open the door”
                    to understanding the sources, to pick up on the larger topics discussed in the
                    introductions, and to illustrate major developments in Jewish history by means of a
                    specific source. At the same time they offer one way of interpreting the source in
                    question.</p>
                <lb/>
                <p>Each source interpretation opens with a brief source description highlighting the
                    most significant aspects and relevant information about the source in a few
                    sentences.</p>
                <lb/>
                <p>On the technical level each source is accompanied by a <hi rendition="#b"><hi
                    rendition="#i">transcription</hi></hi>, which is helpful if not outright
                    necessary for interviews, songs or barely legible handwriting and also enables a
                    full text search.</p>
                <lb/>
                <p>English <hi rendition="#b"><hi rendition="#i">translations</hi></hi> are made
                    available not only for the metatexts (introductions and interpretations), but also
                    for the sources themselves.</p>
                <lb/>
                <p><hi rendition="#b">Metadata</hi> for persons, places, and events are tagged directly
                    in the documents. In addition to targeted searches, this allows for sophisticated
                    indexing tools to be included in the website, thus taking advantage of the potential
                    of electronic publishing. Large parts of these metadata are stored in an <hi
                        rendition="#b"><hi rendition="#i">index</hi></hi>. This concise background
                    information can be found in the “look-up” menu, including an extensible <hi
                        rendition="#b"><hi rendition="#i">glossary</hi></hi> providing further
                    information on persons, for example. Where applicable it will also include external
                    links.</p>
                
            </div>
            <div n="2">
                <head>Paths</head><lb/>
                <p>The digital edition provides many different ways of accessing the sources or
                    questions relating to German-Jewish history. Different paths lead users to the
                    sources and their interpretations. These paths can be accessed via three flags
                    labeled “timeline,” “map,” and “topics.” All sources are assigned a primary date
                    through metadata. This generally is the verifiable date of the source’s creation.
                    For oral history interviews and memoirs the editorial staff has decided to assign two
                    dates – the date when the source was created and the verifiable historic time period
                    it covers. They are integrated into a <hi rendition="#b"><hi rendition="#i"
                        >timeline</hi></hi> based on these dates. For example, those not interested
                    in a diachronic look at a subject throughout the entire course of modern
                    German-Jewish history but in a synchronous look at the history of Hamburg’s Jews in
                    the eighteenth century can run a targeted search for the relevant sources. The
                    decision for a timeline and against established historical epochs was taken in order
                    to ensure opennessfor other historical caesuras. </p>
                <lb/>
                <p>A second way of accessing the material is through a <hi rendition="#b"><hi
                    rendition="#i">map</hi></hi>. In addition to a primary date the sources are
                    also tagged with a primary location – usually the place where they were created –
                    which allows for their location on the map. Since the edition spans several
                    centuries and thus covers several historical, political, and environmental changes,
                    this map is not based on historical data. It is an abstracted map intended mainly
                    for spatial orientation and does not claim historical accuracy. In the current phase
                    of the project, which focuses on Hamburg, the map mostly shows results in the area
                    of northern Germany for obvious reasons. </p>
                <lb/>
                <p>The third way of accessing the sources is through specific <hi rendition="#b"><hi
                    rendition="#i">topics</hi></hi> which are discussed in depth in the
                    introductions, where explicit reference is made to the relevant sources. Each
                    introduction contains links to individual sources related to its subject matter.
                    Since some sources are relevant to various contexts, links to them appear in several
                    of the introductions. </p>                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
